<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Gabe &#8211; here&#039;s what I did&#8230;</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.hereswhatidid.com/author/gabes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/</link>
	<description>The Development Blog of Gabe Shackle</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 15:28:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>ACF Gotchas: Hide on screen</title>
		<link>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/2020/02/acf-gotchas-hide-on-screen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 15:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advanced Custom Fields]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hereswhatidid.com/?p=749</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;ve ever run across issues with the &#8220;Hide on screen&#8221; options in your ACF groups not working or being ignored, be sure to make note of the &#8220;Order No.&#8221; value. Hide on screen options for field groups with a lower order number value will take precendance over higher numbered groups. For example, in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;ve ever run across issues with the &#8220;Hide on screen&#8221; options in your ACF groups not working or being ignored, be sure to make note of the &#8220;Order No.&#8221; value. Hide on screen options for field groups with a lower order number value will take precendance over higher numbered groups.</p>
<p>For example, in the screenshot below you can see two separate custom fields groups that are applied to the same post object:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/acf-gotcha-hideonscreen.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-750" src="https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/acf-gotcha-hideonscreen.png" alt="ACF Gotcha: Hide on screen" width="1000" height="548" srcset="https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/acf-gotcha-hideonscreen.png 1000w, https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/acf-gotcha-hideonscreen-580x318.png 580w, https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/acf-gotcha-hideonscreen-768x421.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></a></p>
<p>When viewing the edit screen for this post, the main Content Editor would still appear even though you&#8217;ve marked it as hidden in the field group on the right. The reason for this is because the field group on the left has a lower Order No. and takes precedance over the group on the right.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Override WooCommerce breadcrumbs with Yoast Primary Categories</title>
		<link>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/2020/02/override-woocommerce-breadcrumbs-with-yoast-primary-categories/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 14:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PHP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snippets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WooCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hereswhatidid.com/?p=738</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The default behavior for WooCommerce breadcrumbs when you have multiple categories selected for a product is to grab the first one found in the list. If you&#8217;re making use of the Primary Category options provided by the Yoast SEO plugin WooCommerce will ignore that setting. Most solutions I&#8217;ve found so far have recommended replacing the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The default behavior for <a href="https://woocommerce.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WooCommerce</a> breadcrumbs when you have multiple categories selected for a product is to grab the first one found in the list. If you&#8217;re making use of the Primary Category options provided by the <a href="https://yoast.com/wordpress/plugins/seo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Yoast SEO</a> plugin WooCommerce will ignore that setting. Most solutions I&#8217;ve found so far have recommended replacing the WooCommerce breadcrumbs with the ones provided by Yoast. If you&#8217;ve done any customization or styling based on the WooCommerce breadcrumbs, the Yoast SEO version is less than ideal. The HTML structure of the Yoast breadcrumbs is a series of nested &lt;span&gt; tags and the divider is manually set through the plugin settings. Not only is this not great from a CSS styling perspective, it&#8217;s completely differnent from the breadcrumb structure provided by WooCommerce and other breadcrumbs plugins.</p>
<p>Another option that exists for integrating the Primary Category in to the WooCommerce breadcrumbs is to simply override the main term that WooCommerce uses to generate the crumbs. The code below demonstrates how to do this using the `woocommerce_breadcrumb_main_term` filter. This code can be added to your theme&#8217;s functions.php file or in a plugin file:</p>
<p><script src="https://gist.github.com/hereswhatidid/fb9152a11bc359fa32772e4d18f01c9a.js"></script></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Setting up GIT deployment on Nexcess hosting</title>
		<link>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/2020/02/setting-up-git-deployment-on-nexcess-hosting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 03:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nexcess]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hereswhatidid.com/?p=727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Setting up GIT deployment for hosts that do not have it baked in to the control panel can be daunting if you&#8217;ve never done it before. After Googling around quite a bit I&#8217;ve put together a step-by-step process that makes it fairly straight forward. Step 1: Connect and gather directory information The first step is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Setting up GIT deployment for hosts that do not have it baked in to the control panel can be daunting if you&#8217;ve never done it before. After Googling around quite a bit I&#8217;ve put together a step-by-step process that makes it fairly straight forward.</p>
<h4>Step 1: Connect and gather directory information</h4>
<p>The first step is to make sure you have SSH access to the host machine as well as confirming that GIT is installed and available. Once you have done this you can begin by connecting to the host via SSH:</p>
<p><code>ssh SSHUSERNAME@SSHDOMAINorIP</code></p>
<p>Once connected, run this command to get the directory information that will be used later on:</p>
<p><code>pwd</code></p>
<p>This command will list the path to the current directory should be something like /home/USERNAME/</p>
<h4>Step 2: Create directories and initialize GIT</h4>
<p>Create the directory for your new, empty GIT repository. Replace SITENAME with the domain name for the site or whatever you want it to be:</p>
<p><code>mkdir repo/SITENAME.git</code></p>
<p>Then switch to that newly created directory and initialize GIT:</p>
<p><code>cd repo/SITENAME.git<br />
git init --bare</code></p>
<h4>Step 3: Create post-receive hook to deploy code changes</h4>
<p>Hooks in GIT are a way to execute scripts after specific events occur. In this case we want to use the &#8216;post-receive&#8217; hook. This hook runs after everything else has occurred during a GIT push.</p>
<p>Switch to the GIT directory’s `hooks` subdirectory</p>
<p><code>cd hooks</code></p>
<p>Create and open a file named `post-receive`</p>
<p><code>nano post-receive</code></p>
<p>This will open a nano editor within Terminal for editing the `post-receive` file.<br />
Grab the contents of `post-receive` in this GIST and update them to match your data:</p>
<p><script src="https://gist.github.com/hereswhatidid/ffe28538278e4a3566e7d2053e9c6456.js?file=post-receive"></script></p>
<p>Paste the updated contents in to the nano document then save and close the document.</p>
<p><code>ctrl+o</code></p>
<p>Hit enter to confirm the file name which should be `post-receive`.</p>
<p><code>ctrl+x</code></p>
<p>Finally, set the correct permissions on the file so that it can process the requests.</p>
<p><code>chmod +x post-receive</code></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Populate an ACF drop down field with a list of GravityForm forms</title>
		<link>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/2018/09/populate-an-acf-drop-down-field-with-a-list-of-gravityform-forms/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 16:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advanced Custom Fields]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GravityForms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PHP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hereswhatidid.com/?p=703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here is an example script showing how to populate an Advanced Custom Fields drop down with any forms you have currently enabled that have been created by the GravityForms plugin:]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here is an example script showing how to populate an <a href="https://www.advancedcustomfields.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Advanced Custom Fields</a> drop down with any forms you have currently enabled that have been created by the <a href="https://www.gravityforms.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GravityForms</a> plugin:</p>
<p><script src="https://gist.github.com/hereswhatidid/eaee026f172e53b8d79c20d6c1666be6.js"></script></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Using MySQL to conditionally update WordPress post meta data</title>
		<link>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/2018/04/using-mysql-to-conditionally-update-wordpress-post-meta-data/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 15:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MySQL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WooCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hereswhatidid.com/?p=691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a recent bulk product import for a WooCommerce installation we noticed an issue with the gallery images. The featured image for each product was set to the first image within the gallery for that product. This created a duplicate image issue where the image gallery on the product detail page would show the first [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a recent bulk product import for a WooCommerce installation we noticed an issue with the gallery images. The featured image for each product was set to the first image within the gallery for that product. This created a duplicate image issue where the image gallery on the product detail page would show the first image twice. The suggestion from the plugin&#8217;s documentation was to rerun the import specifically targeting those fields to fix the issue. This was less than ideal as we were dealing with a product list that was nearly 3,000 items long and took 20-25 minutes to fully import.</p>
<p>Because I knew the underlying data was fine, it was just being duplicated, I decided to use a MySQL query to update the database directly rather than running another import. Here is the query I ended up with:</p>
<blockquote><p><code>UPDATE wp_postmeta a<br />
JOIN wp_postmeta b<br />
ON a.post_id = b.post_id<br />
SET b.meta_value = REPLACE(b.meta_value, CONCAT(a.meta_value, ','), '')<br />
WHERE a.meta_key = '_thumbnail_id' AND b.meta_key = '_product_image_gallery';<br />
</code></p></blockquote>
<p>Because of the way that WordPress stores post meta I had to run a join on the wp_postmeta table against itself. Here is a break down of each line of the query:</p>
<blockquote><p><code>UPDATE wp_postmeta a<br />
JOIN wp_postmeta b</code></p></blockquote>
<p>Here I am selecting the wp_postmeta table and joining it to itself in order to grab the two separate meta data values. The <code>a</code> table is for the <code>_thumbnail_id</code> field and the <code>b</code> table is for the <code>_product_image_gallery</code> field.</p>
<blockquote><p><code>ON a.post_id = b.post_id</code></p></blockquote>
<p>Now we use the <code>post_id</code> column to join together the rows by the post that they are associated with.</p>
<blockquote><p><code>SET b.meta_value = REPLACE(b.meta_value, CONCAT(a.meta_value, ','), '')</code></p></blockquote>
<p>After selecting and joining the tables I am setting the <code>meta_value</code> of the <code>b</code> table to be the value of the <code>meta_value</code> column with the duplicate image ID removed. It was made simpler because of the fact that I knew that the first value in that <code>_product_image_gallery</code> meta value was the duplicate. This meant I only had to search at the beginning and not worry about whether or not it was followed by a comma.</p>
<p>One important note: the reason I&#8217;m specifically targeting the <code>b.meta_value</code> column is because the <code>b</code> table is the table within the join that is targeting the <code>_product_image_gallery</code> meta field. If I were to use the <code>a</code> table it would assign the updated value to the <code>_image_id</code> meta field.</p>
<blockquote><p><code>WHERE a.meta_key = '_thumbnail_id' AND b.meta_key = '_product_image_gallery';</code></p></blockquote>
<p>Finally I am establishing which meta fields that I&#8217;m looking to target with the query.</p>
<p>By using this MySQL approach to fixing the meta data I was able to fix the meta fields with a single command that took roughly 3 seconds to process rather than running another full product import.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Add ACF fields to product attributes in WooCommerce</title>
		<link>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/2016/08/add-acf-fields-product-attributes-woocommerce/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 13:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advanced Custom Fields]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WooCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hereswhatidid.com/?p=658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For a client&#8217;s site we wanted to add some ACF fields to the Edit Term page for global attributes. If the attribute list were fixed, this would be a simple task of targeting the specific taxonomies in the field group&#8217;s location parameter. What complicated this particular instance is that we wanted ALL attribute edit pages to have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For a client&#8217;s site we wanted to add some <a href="https://www.advancedcustomfields.com/">ACF</a> fields to the Edit Term page for global attributes. If the attribute list were fixed, this would be a simple task of targeting the specific taxonomies in the field group&#8217;s location parameter. What complicated this particular instance is that we wanted ALL attribute edit pages to have these custom fields and the client had the ability to add or remove attribute via the admin. This meant that we had to be able to gather all the attribute types and target them for our field group.</p>
<p>This turned out to be a fairly straight-forward task. By using the WooCommerce function <a href="https://docs.woocommerce.com/wc-apidocs/function-wc_get_attribute_taxonomy_names.html">wc_get_attribute_taxonomy_names()</a> we can create a set of location rules that are dynamically created which will target all existing global attribute types.</p>
<p>Here is the complete code which will add a tab and sample image field to all global attribute Term Edit pages:</p>
<script src="https://gist.github.com/hereswhatidid/9ba2bfe386a4eafb0bc82a11a748416b.js"></script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>List variation SKUs within the WooCommerce product edit screen</title>
		<link>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/2016/05/list-variation-skus-within-woocommerce-product-edit-screen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 16:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JavaScript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jQuery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WooCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hereswhatidid.com/?p=655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This snippet will replace the existing post ID displayed in the WooCommerce product edit screen with the variation&#8217;s SKU if one exists. Often times the variation SKU is far more useful to an admin than the internal WordPress post ID so having it displayed on the edit screen makes the administration process much easier.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This snippet will replace the existing post ID displayed in the WooCommerce product edit screen with the variation&#8217;s SKU if one exists. Often times the variation SKU is far more useful to an admin than the internal WordPress post ID so having it displayed on the edit screen makes the administration process much easier.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/woocommerce-sku-snippet.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-656" src="https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/woocommerce-sku-snippet.png" alt="woocommerce-sku-snippet" width="650" height="272" srcset="https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/woocommerce-sku-snippet.png 650w, https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/woocommerce-sku-snippet-580x243.png 580w" sizes="(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px" /></a></p>
<script src="https://gist.github.com/hereswhatidid/88ffd83eb2e2840c43e589f30f335b4f.js"></script>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Customize ACF WYSIWYG Input Styles</title>
		<link>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/2015/08/customize-acf-wysiwyg-input-styles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 03:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advanced Custom Fields]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jQuery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PHP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hereswhatidid.com/?p=614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Often times, a design will call for separate areas within a page to have their own unique styles applied to them. Whether it&#8217;s a different background color, font size, or available space, editing those areas can be frustrating when the backend editor does not have those same styles. By default, ACF does not have the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Often times, a design will call for separate areas within a page to have their own unique styles applied to them. Whether it&#8217;s a different background color, font size, or available space, editing those areas can be frustrating when the backend editor does not have those same styles. By default, ACF does not have the ability to specify a body class for the WYSIWYG editor&#8217;s iframed body tag. (a prototype solution has been developed) Thankfully, ACF does have a JavaScript filter available that allows us to directly modify those classes, and with a little trickery, we can use the field options to give our WYSIWYG fields unique classes and thus styles.</p>
<p>The filter that is used for this example is &#8216;<a href="http://www.advancedcustomfields.com/resources/adding-custom-javascript-fields/" target="_blank">wysiwyg_tinymce_settings</a>&#8216;. This filter makes it possible to edit the TinyMCE  settings immediately before the field is initialized. What I decided to do was to make use of the existing CSS wrapper field in the ACF admin:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/hwid-acf-wysiwyg-body-class.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-616 size-medium" src="https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/hwid-acf-wysiwyg-body-class-580x195.png" alt="ACF WYSIWYG Class Input" width="580" height="195" srcset="https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/hwid-acf-wysiwyg-body-class-580x195.png 580w, https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/hwid-acf-wysiwyg-body-class.png 812w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" /></a></p>
<p>Then, using the previously mentioned filter, I grab those values and apply them to the WYSIWYG editor&#8217;s iframe body tag:</p>
<p><script src="https://gist.github.com/hereswhatidid/f88390659cbf1fd6a03d.js?file=custom-acf-wysiwyg-css.php"></script></p>
<p>Now, if I specify the correct class names within my &#8216;editor-styles.css&#8217; file, the editor will get the custom styling I&#8217;ve set.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-617 size-full" src="https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/hwid-acf-wysiwyg-example.png" alt="ACF Custom WYSIWYG CSS Example" width="691" height="503" srcset="https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/hwid-acf-wysiwyg-example.png 691w, https://www.hereswhatidid.com/media/hwid-acf-wysiwyg-example-580x422.png 580w" sizes="(max-width: 691px) 100vw, 691px" /></p>
<p>Now I can easily style all the ACF WYSIWYG fields in my admin so that they exactly reflect how the content will look on the front end.</p>
<p>The full code is <a href="https://gist.github.com/hereswhatidid/f88390659cbf1fd6a03d" target="_blank">available on Github</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creating custom product tabs in WooCommerce Storefront with ACF</title>
		<link>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/2015/08/creating-custom-product-tabs-in-woocommerce-storefront-with-acf/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 21:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advanced Custom Fields]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WooCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hereswhatidid.com/?p=604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recently I was tasked with adding some custom tabs to a WooCommerce store using the Storefront theme. There was a commercial solution available but I felt this was something that could fairly easily be done via Advanced Custom Fields and the built-in Storefront filters. 30 minutes later and a solution was in place.  Here&#8217;s a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently I was tasked with adding some custom tabs to a WooCommerce store using the <a href="http://www.woothemes.com/storefront/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Storefront theme</a>. There was a commercial solution available but I felt this was something that could fairly easily be done via <a href="http://www.advancedcustomfields.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Advanced Custom Fields</a> and the built-in Storefront filters. 30 minutes later and a solution was in place.  Here&#8217;s a basic run down of how I was able to pull in the content of a <a href="http://www.advancedcustomfields.com/resources/repeater/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Repeater</a> field:</p>
<p>First, create the content fields within ACF. I used just a basic repeater that contains a text field for the tab title and a WYSIWYG field for the tab content. For the example code, the repeater was named &#8220;tabs&#8221; and it&#8217;s sub fields are named &#8220;tab_title&#8221; and &#8220;tab_content&#8221;.</p>
<p>Next, I just had to tie these tabs in to the existing WooCommerce filter &#8220;<a href="https://github.com/woothemes/woocommerce/blob/master/templates/single-product/tabs/tabs.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">woocommerce_product_tabs</a>&#8221; (<a href="http://docs.woothemes.com/document/editing-product-data-tabs/">more details</a>) which allows you to modify the existing tabs for each product on it&#8217;s detail page. I grabbed the assigned tabs from the &#8216;tabs&#8217; ACF field. Stepping through these tabs I added them to the incoming &#8216;$tabs&#8217; variable within the filter.  The required properties for each tab are:</p>
<ul>
<li>title &#8211; The title of the tab</li>
<li>priority &#8211; The order in which the tab should appear among the other tabs</li>
<li>callback &#8211; The name of the function to call to get the content of the tab</li>
</ul>
<p>You&#8217;ll notice in my code I&#8217;m adding a fourth property &#8220;tabContent&#8221;. This is a custom property used by my content generating function to get the WYSIWYG content to display within the tab.<script src="https://gist.github.com/hereswhatidid/3654843605397fe0e484.js?file=custom-woo-acf-tabs.php"></script><br />
And that&#8217;s all there is to it. Of course there are plenty of areas to improve this small bit of code. For example, I plan on adding in a &#8220;Global Tabs&#8221; area that would let the client specify global tabs that should appear under all products or even products just within specific Categories. Additionally, I also will be adding a field to control the value of the &#8216;priority&#8217; property rather than auto-generating.</p>
<p>The full code including the ACF Repeater declaration can be <a href="https://gist.github.com/hereswhatidid/3654843605397fe0e484" target="_blank" rel="noopener">viewed on GitHub</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ImportBuddy &#8220;ERROR #83893a: unable to decode JSON restore data &#8220;. Restore halted.&#8221; error</title>
		<link>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/2015/03/importbuddy-error-83893a-unable-to-decode-json-restore-data-restore-halted-error/</link>
					<comments>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/2015/03/importbuddy-error-83893a-unable-to-decode-json-restore-data-restore-halted-error/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 18:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BackupBuddy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GoDaddy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ImportBuddy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hereswhatidid.com/?p=586</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;ve run across this error when trying to restore a site via the iThemes ImportBuddy tool: ERROR #83893a: unable to decode JSON restore data ``. Restore halted. Here are a couple steps you can follow to diagnose the issue: Verify the source of the issue &#8211; Look in your browser&#8217;s debug console and check [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;ve run across this error when trying to restore a site via the iThemes ImportBuddy tool:</p>
<pre>ERROR #83893a: unable to decode JSON restore data ``. Restore halted.</pre>
<p>Here are a couple steps you can follow to diagnose the issue:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Verify the source of the issue &#8211; </strong>Look in your browser&#8217;s debug console and check for something like &#8220;Uncaught TypeError: undefined is not a function&#8221;. Jump to the source of the error.  In my case it was the &#8220;.on()&#8221; function not being declared.  This is a dead giveaway that something wonky is going on with the loaded version of jQuery.</li>
<li><strong>Check the loaded version of jQuery &#8211;</strong> Run this code in your debug console to verify the current version:
<pre>jQuery.fn.jquery</pre>
<p>If that returns anything below 1.11.x you are viewing an old version of the jQuery library.  You can double check this by browsing directly to the included jquery.js file.  The URL should be something like: http://YOURSITEURL/importbuddy/js/jquery.js</li>
<li><strong>Check the loaded version of jQueryUI Tooltip &#8211;</strong> This was another script that was loading improperly for me as well.  Browse directly to the tooltip.js file by using a URL like: http://YOURSITEURL/importbuddy/js/tooltip.js</li>
</ol>
<p>What appears to be causing these issues is the hosting provider has a cached version of those specific files and is serving that rather than the actual files on your server.</p>
<p>One possible workaround is to start the ImportBuddy process and clear the site&#8217;s cache after the /importbuddy/ directory has been created during the first step of the import process but before it has restored any files.  This can be tricky since ImportBuddy will put your site in to maintenance mode once it starts so you&#8217;ll have to delete the &#8220;.maintenance&#8221; file if your hosting provider requires you to be logged in to WordPress in order to clear the cache (this is the case with GoDaddy Managed WordPress hosting).  After you&#8217;ve cleared the cache, restart the import process and verify that the correct files are now showing up.</p>
<p>If clearing the cache does not fix it there&#8217;s a more heavy-handed fix that will work but requires editing the ImportBuddy code:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Change the plugin version &#8211;</strong> Changing the plugin version to a much higher number will also cause the server to not use the cached version.  You can do this by opening the &#8216;/importbuddy/init.php&#8217; file on your destination server and set the version declaration to something like 55555.  Once you&#8217;ve done this, restart the ImportBuddy process and verify that the scripts are loading correctly.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.hereswhatidid.com/2015/03/importbuddy-error-83893a-unable-to-decode-json-restore-data-restore-halted-error/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
